



I am a frontend developer who loves using code to engage people. I have worn many hats in my career, and finding the right tool for the job when solving hard problems in the ever-changing frontend world is what I do best. Whether it's calculating the perfect bezier curve for an eye-catching animation or streamlining team processes through modular component libraries, my enthusiasm for crafting great user experience through frontend best practices and passion for experimentation runs deep.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Lead Frontend Developer**

Topbox, Kansas City, MO (Remote from Chicago, IL)

September 2016 to September 2019

Topbox data mines a company's communication data and uses machine learning along with well crafted analytics to provide insight about how people are feeling about their brand. At Topbox, I led a frontend team to build multiple iterations of an extremely data-rich application and all visual component libraries to support it.

- Successfully went from being a developer that designed features visually as well as molding their user experience to leading a team of developers working in tandem with a user experience expert.
- Spearheaded the product transition from a closed, proprietary user interface and analytic framework to React. This improvement pivoted the product into significant hard cost savings and significantly reduced technical debt.
- Pioneered better code quality practices such as full coverage unit testing and linting, as well as peer-to-peer reviews on all pull requests.
- Worked with a varied-skill research team to architect technology that aligned innovative features with the Topbox sales team's goal to keep ahead of their competitors.

### **Frontend Developer**

Dwolla, Des Moines, IA (Remote from Kansas City, MO)

March 2014 to August 2016

Dwolla is transforming e-commerce by transitioning traditional plastic card-based transactions into direct - connect systems that save users money. As part of the frontend development team, I worked to enhance user interface and streamline the way people move millions of dollars with Dwolla each and every day. At Dwolla, I provided leadership for technical frontend development, including unit testing, validation, and other best practices of web applications.

- 🔰 Developed tools to constantly monitor and assess page speed throughout the site.
- Used Node, D3, and React to build internal data monitoring tools.
- Established documentation for frontend standards by use of exemplars, react component libraries, and the development of extensible and adaptable style tiles.

# Interactive Web Developer Platform Lead

MMGY Global, Kansas City, MO

June 2011 to March 2014

MMGY Global is the largest and most integrated travel marketing firm in the world. Their mission is simple: help travel companies grow revenue by motivating their customers. At MMGY, I was an expert interface developer leading an interdisciplinary team of interactive developers. Together, we conceptualized, created, produced, and extended overall brand and design direction online. On a day-to-day basis, I constantly pushed for innovation and excellence within the company by mentoring junior developers, introducing new technologies, and reimagining ways to communicate.

- Developed, maintained, and led the ramp up into responsive website creation that continually evolves to utilize new web technology trends.
- Key player in our laboratory team which discovers new technologies, new uses for existing technologies including microcontrollers like Arduino, and invents ways to apply these practices to our clientele.
- Stream lined workflow and reorganized the development process to enhance work sharing, improve interdisciplinary collaboration, and increase profitability.
- Direct collaboration with Art Directors, Copywriters, Designers, and other Developers to ensure best practices for optimized web performance and memorable end-user experience.
- Internal coordination with sales, project managers, and project staff to develop budgets, timelines, storyboards, and risk projections associated with advanced multimedia applications and animation
- Performed code reviews and provided technical guidance for team members and junior developers.

### **MultiMedia Director**

Salva O'Renick, Kansas City, MO

July 2005 to 2011

Salva O'Renick is a sales and marketing communications firm with a strong focus on financial and animal health clientele. At Salva O'Renick, I spearheaded all project responsibilities covering motion and audio, working primarily with Flash content for the web. My technical capabilities allowed me to develop cutting-edge, resellable applications that revolutionized how Salva O'Renick produced and marketed video and interactive animation.

## **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Arts in Studio Art** *Photograpy/Graphic Design* University of Missouri Kansas City - Awarded 2003. **Bachelor of Arts in Communications** *Mass Media* University of Missouri Kansas City - Awarded 2003. **Associate of Arts** Metropolitan Community Colleges, Lees Summit, Missouri - Awarded 2001.

## TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE BASE

- Object oriented programming concepts and coding, primarily with JavaScript.
- Agile Development practices and knowledge to develop clean, refactored, and reusable code.
- Web languages and communication, such as JavaScript, Node, Angular, React, HTML, and CSS.
- Web Development from conceptualization, design, front-end development and backend-development.
- Frontend code quality through pull request reviews, third-party validation, and semantic markup reviews.
- lutilization of efficient tools such as Git, Webpack, Sass, React on a day to day basis.
- Use and development of fully robust content management systems.
- Linux web server barebones setup, optimization, and automated deployment.
- Adobe products: Flash, Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Premiere, and Audition.
- Computer hardware modification and trouble shooting from both low and high levels.
- Froduction and post-production equipment and processing for video production and photography for professional client-based projects with small teams.

References furnished upon request